	var quizArray = [{
		"id":"0",
		"question":"Geographically, the Philippines is located in",
		"choice1":"East Asia",
		"choice2":"Southeast Asia",
		"choice3":"South Asia",
		"choice4":"West Asia",
		"correct":"Southeast Asia"
	},
	{
		"id":"1",
		"question":"The northernmost island of the Philippines.",
		"choice1":"Omapay",
		"choice2":"Batanes",
		"choice3":"Babuyan",
		"choice4":"Y'ami",
		"correct":"Y'ami"
	},
	{
		"id":"2",
		"question":"The Badjaos are more popularly known  as the :",
		"choice1":"The wanderers",
		"choice2":"Muslim divers",
		"choice3":"Sea gypsies",
		"choice4":"Coral gatherers",
		"correct":"Sea gypsies"
	},
	{
		"id":"3",
		"question":"Which country had the Philippines as its colony from 1898 to 1946, except for some years during World War II?",
		"choice1":"Portugal",
		"choice2":"USA",
		"choice3":"UK",
		"choice4":"Belgium",
		"correct":"USA"
	},
	{
		"id":"4",
		"question":" Which country had the Philippines as its colony for more than 300 years?",
		"choice1":"Spain",
		"choice2":"Italy",
		"choice3":"France",
		"choice4":"England",
		"correct":"Spain"
	},
	{
		"id":"5",
		"question":"Who of the following explorers arrived in the Philippines in 1521?",
		"choice1":"Christopher Columbus",
		"choice2":"Ferdinand Magellan",
		"choice3":"Vasco da Gama",
		"choice4":"James Cook",
		"correct":"Ferdinand Magellan"
	},
	{
		"id":"6",
		"question":" The predominant religion of the Philippines.",
		"choice1":"Christianity",
		"choice2":"Islam",
		"choice3":"Buddhism",
		"choice4":"Judaism",
		"correct":"Christianity"
	},
	{
		"id":"7",
		"question":"Founded the la Liga Filipina.",
		"choice1":"Andres Bonifacio",
		"choice2":"Jose Rizal",
		"choice3":"Emilio Aguinaldo",
		"choice4":"Emilio Jacinto",
		"correct":"Jose Rizal"
	},
	{
		"id":"8",
		"question":"Who was the first Miss Philippines?",
		"choice1":"Margi Moran",
		"choice2":"Mirriam Quiambao",
		"choice3":"Evangeline Castro",
		"choice4":"Gloria Diaz",
		"correct":"Evangeline Castro"
	},
	{
		"id":"9",
		"question":"The first Filipino recording artist.",
		"choice1":"Imelda Papin",
		"choice2":"Pilita Corales",
		"choice3":"Margi Moran",
		"choice4":"Maria Carpena",
		"correct":"Maria Carpena"
	},
	{
		"id":"10",
		"question":"The first Filipino Olympian.",
		"choice1":"Paeng Nepomuceno",
		"choice2":"David Nepomuceno",
		"choice3":"Akiko Thompson",
		"choice4":"Efren Bata Reyes",
		"correct":"David Nepomuceno"
	},
	{
		"id":"11",
		"question":" The last Sultan of Sulu.",
		"choice1":"Haji Butu ",
		"choice2":"Sultan Kudarat",
		"choice3":"Jamalul Kiram II",
		"choice4":"Abu Bakr",
		"correct":"Jamalul Kiram II"
	},
	{
		"id":"12",
		"question":"How many Filipino Vice-Presidents later became President?",
		"choice1":"7",
		"choice2":"6",
		"choice3":"5",
		"choice4":"4",
		"correct":"6"
	},
	{
		"id":"13",
		"question":"The oldest existing city in the Philippines?",
		"choice1":"Cebu",
		"choice2":"Davao",
		"choice3":"Olongapo",
		"choice4":"Cavite",
		"correct":"Cebu"
	},
	{
		"id":"14",
		"question":"The longest river in the Philippines?",
		"choice1":"Pasig River",
		"choice2":"Abra River",
		"choice3":"Cagayan River",
		"choice4":"Angat River",
		"correct":"Cagayan River"
	},
	{
		"id":"15",
		"question":"Who was the first woman senator?",
		"choice1":"Geronima Pecson",
		"choice2":"Miriam Defensor Santiago",
		"choice3":"Grace Poe",
		"choice4":"Pia Cayetano",
		"correct":"Geronima Pecson"
	},
	{
		"id":"16",
		"question":"Who was the first Archbishop of the Philippines?",
		"choice1":"Marlo Mendoza Peralta",
		"choice2":"Domingo Salazar",
		"choice3":"Socrates B. Villegas",
		"choice4":"Romulo T. Dela Cruz",
		"correct":"Domingo Salazar"
	},
	{
		"id":"17",
		"question":"The first woman to top the Philippine BAR Examination.",
		"choice1":"Josefa Diokno",
		"choice2":"Geronima Pecson",
		"choice3":"Tina Munoz Palma",
		"choice4":"Tecla San Andres Ziga",
		"correct":"Tecla San Andres Ziga"
	},
	{
		"id":"18",
		"question":"The first president of the Katipunan. ",
		"choice1":"Deodato Arellano",
		"choice2":"Teodoro Agoncillo",
		"choice3":"Juan Arellano",
		"choice4":"Andres Bonifacio ",
		"correct":"Deodato Arellano"
	},
	{
		"id":"19",
		"question":"The first book printed in the Philippines?",
		"choice1":"El Filibusterismo",
		"choice2":"Noli Me Tangere",
		"choice3":"Doctrina Christiana",
		"choice4":"Mi Ultimo Adios",
		"correct":"Doctrina Christiana"
	},
	{
		"id":"20",
		"question":" He was also known as Hermano Pule.",
		"choice1":"Aurelio Tolentino",
		"choice2":"Pedro Feced",
		"choice3":"Apolinario de la Cruz",
		"choice4":"Juan Ponce",
		"correct":"Apolinario de la Cruz"
	},
	{
		"id":"21",
		"question":"The chief advisor of Gen. Emilio?",
		"choice1":"Pedro Paterno",
		"choice2":"Apolinario Mabini",
		"choice3":"Jose Rizal",
		"choice4":"Felipe Calderon ",
		"correct":"Apolinario Mabini"
	},
	{
		"id":"22",
		"question":"The first political party in the Philippines organized on December 23, 1900 by wealthy Filipino illustrados.",
		"choice1":"Nacionalista Party",
		"choice2":"Federal Party",
		"choice3":"Liberal Party",
		"choice4":"Partido Nacional Progresibo",
		"correct":"Federal Party"
	},
	{
		"id":"23",
		"question":"What does “KKK” stand for?",
		"choice1":"Kataas-taasan, Kabuti-butihang Katipunan",
		"choice2":"Kagalang-galangan, Kataas-taasang Katipunan",
		"choice3":"Kataas-taasan, Kagalang-galangang Katipunan",
		"choice4":"Kataas-taasan, Kaganda-gandahang Katipunan",
		"correct":"Kataas-taasan, Kagalang-galangang Katipunan"
	},
	{
		"id":"24",
		"question":"What was the name of the only ship to complete Magellan’s expedition?",
		"choice1":"Victoria",
		"choice2":"Galleon",
		"choice3":"Aurora",
		"choice4":"Vicente",
		"correct":"Victoria"
	},
	{
		"id":"25",
		"question":"Who earned the title “Hero of Tirad Pass”. ",
		"choice1":"Gen. Gregorio Del Pilar",
		"choice2":"Emilio Aguinaldo",
		"choice3":"Apolinario Mabini",
		"choice4":"Andres Bonifacio",
		"correct":"Gen. Gregorio Del Pilar"
	},
	{
		"id":"26",
		"question":"The fighting nurse of Bulacan, who was called Mother of “Biak-na-Bato”.",
		"choice1":"Agueda Kahabagan",
		"choice2":"Teresa Magbanua",
		"choice3":"Juana Magsilog",
		"choice4":"Trinidad Tecson",
		"correct":"Trinidad Tecson"
	},
	{
		"id":"27",
		"question":"When did Gen. Del Pilar subdued the cavalry led by Major J.F. Bell and killed Col. J.M.Stotsenburg?",
		"choice1":"April 19, 1899",
		"choice2":"April 23, 1899",
		"choice3":"April 19, 1988",
		"choice4":"April 23, 1988",
		"correct":"April 23, 1899"
	},
	{
		"id":"28",
		"question":"Known as the “Visayas Joan of Arc”  because of her successful military exploits on the Panay battlefields. ",
		"choice1":"Agueda Kahabagan",
		"choice2":"Teresa Magbanua",
		"choice3":"Juana Magsilog",
		"choice4":"Trinidad Tecson",
		"correct":"Teresa Magbanua"
	},
	{
		"id":"29",
		"question":"Title given to Agueda Kahabagan, woman-general  of Laguna whose has a knowledge of martial arts .",
		"choice1":"Visayas Joan of Arc",
		"choice2":"Biak-na-Bato",
		"choice3":"Hero of Tirad Pass",
		"choice4":"Tagalog Joan of Arc",
		"correct":"Tagalog Joan of Arc"
	},
	{
		"id":"30",
		"question":"What constitution was not immediately proclaimed by Aguinaldo due to Mabini's objections?",
		"choice1":"1987 Constitution",
		"choice2":"Malolos Constitution",
		"choice3":"1989 Constitution",
		"choice4":"Malolas Constitution",
		"correct":"Malolos Constitution"
	},
	{
		"id":"31",
		"question":"Cry of Balintawak ",
		"choice1":" “Long Lives Filipino” ",
		"choice2":" “Long Live The Philippines” ",
		"choice3":" “Long Life Filipinos” ",
		"choice4":" “Live The Philippines” ",
		"correct":" “Long Live The Philippines” "
	},
	{
		"id":"32",
		"question":"Subsequently  inaugurated the First Philippine Republic.",
		"choice1":"June 12, 1898",
		"choice2":"January 12, 1898",
		"choice3":"June 23, 1899",
		"choice4":"January 23, 1899",
		"correct":"January 23, 1899"
	},
	{
		"id":"33",
		"question":"Aguinaldo proclaimed Philippine Independence",
		"choice1":"January 23, 1899",
		"choice2":"June 12, 1898",
		"choice3":"January 12, 1898",
		"choice4":"June 23, 1899",
		"correct":"June 12, 1898"
	},
	{
		"id":"34",
		"question":"Signed by the representatives from Spain and United States to formally end the Spanish-American war.",
		"choice1":"Bates Treaty",
		"choice2":"Murphy Treaty",
		"choice3":"Treaty of Paris",
		"choice4":"Forbes Treaty",
		"correct":"Treaty of Paris"
	},
	{
		"id":"35",
		"question":"Issued his Benevolent Assimilation policy towards the Philippines",
		"choice1":"President  McKinley",
		"choice2":"George Dewey",
		"choice3":"General McArthur",
		"choice4":"General Wesley Merritt",
		"correct":"President  McKinley"
	},
	{
		"id":"36",
		"question":"The first organic law which provided for the granting of Philippine Independence.",
		"choice1":"Jones Law",
		"choice2":"Tydings-McDuffie Law",
		"choice3":"Hare-Hawes Cutting Law",
		"choice4":"McHawes Law",
		"correct":"Jones Law"
	},
	{
		"id":"37",
		"question":"Inaugurated on November 15, 1935.",
		"choice1":"Philippine Assembly",
		"choice2":"Philippine Independence",
		"choice3":"First Philippine Republic",
		"choice4":"Philippine Commonwealth",
		"correct":"Philippine Commonwealth"
	},
	{
		"id":"38",
		"question":"Owned the first Filipino bank.",
		"choice1":"Rodriguez Mercado",
		"choice2":"Antonio Urbiztondo",
		"choice3":"Francisco Rodriguez",
		"choice4":"Francisco Antonio",
		"correct":"Francisco Rodriguez"
	},
	{
		"id":"39",
		"question":"The first Spanish bank.",
		"choice1":"Rodriguez Bank",
		"choice2":"Bank of the Philippine Island",
		"choice3":"Banco De Oro",
		"choice4":"Land Bank",
		"correct":"Bank of the Philippine Island"
	},
	{
		"id":"40",
		"question":"Owned the first Spanish bank.",
		"choice1":"Rodriguez Mercado",
		"choice2":"Antonio Urbiztondo",
		"choice3":"Francisco Rodriguez",
		"choice4":"Francisco Antonio",
		"correct":"Antonio Urbiztondo"
	},
	{
		"id":"41",
		"question":"The First Filipino Bank.",
		"choice1":"Rodriguez Bank",
		"choice2":"Bank of the Philippine Island",
		"choice3":"Banco De Oro",
		"choice4":"Land Bank",
		"correct":"Rodriguez Bank"
	},
	{
		"id":"42",
		"question":"An organization formed  by the first group of businessmen which loaned money in Manila.",
		"choice1":"Obras Pias",
		"choice2":"Obra Banco",
		"choice3":"Banco Pias",
		"choice4":"Obra Pias",
		"correct":"Obras Pias"
	},
	{
		"id":"43",
		"question":"The First Governor General.",
		"choice1":"Diego Delos Rios",
		"choice2":"Pedro Abad Santos",
		"choice3":"Miguel Lopez de Legazpi",
		"choice4":"Carlos Ma. Dela Torre",
		"correct":"Miguel Lopez de Legazpi"
	},
	{
		"id":"44",
		"question":"The first Lighthouse.",
		"choice1":"Parola",
		"choice2":"Parole",
		"choice3":"Farole",
		"choice4":"Farola",
		"correct":"Farola"
	},
	{
		"id":"45",
		"question":"Let alone business policy by Adam Smith.",
		"choice1":"encomienda system",
		"choice2":"laissez-faire",
		"choice3":"real-situado",
		"choice4":"martines",
		"correct":"laissez-faire"
	},
	{
		"id":"46",
		"question":"The most popular Tagalog epic during the 17th  century.",
		"choice1":"Florante at Laura",
		"choice2":"Cenaculo",
		"choice3":"Duplo",
		"choice4":"Karagatan",
		"correct":"Florante at Laura"
	},
	{
		"id":"47",
		"question":"Specified that the Philippines rightfully belonged to Portugal.",
		"choice1":"Bates Treaty",
		"choice2":"Murphy Treaty",
		"choice3":"Treaty of Paris",
		"choice4":"Treaty of Tordesillas",
		"correct":"Treaty of Tordesillas"
	},
	{
		"id":"48",
		"question":"Led the longest revolt in Philippine history.",
		"choice1":"Magalat",
		"choice2":"Diego Silang",
		"choice3":"Dagohoy",
		"choice4":"Tapar",
		"correct":"Dagohoy"
	},
	{
		"id":"49",
		"question":"The official newspaper of the reform movement.",
		"choice1":"La Liga Filipina",
		"choice2":"La Solidaridad",
		"choice3":"España en Filipinas",
		"choice4":"La Filipino",
		"correct":"La Solidaridad"
	},
	{
		"id":"50",
		"question":"First editor of La Solidaridad.",
		"choice1":"Marcelo H. Del Pilar",
		"choice2":"Antonio Luna",
		"choice3":"Graciano Lopez Jaena",
		"choice4":"Mariano Ponce",
		"correct":"Graciano Lopez Jaena"
	},
	{
		"id":"51",
		"question":"The novelist among the Filipino Reformists.",
		"choice1":"Antonio Luna",
		"choice2":"Jose Ma. Panganiban",
		"choice3":"Jose Rizal",
		"choice4":"Mariano Ponce",
		"correct":"Jose Rizal"
	},
	{
		"id":"52",
		"question":"The courageous and brilliant warlord used “Taga-ilog” as his pen-name.",
		"choice1":"Antonio Luna",
		"choice2":"Jose Ma. Panganiban",
		"choice3":"Jose Rizal",
		"choice4":"Mariano Ponce",
		"correct":"Antonio Luna"
	},
	{
		"id":"53",
		"question":"President of Solidaridad.",
		"choice1":"Manuel Santa Maria",
		"choice2":"Jose Ma. Panganiban",
		"choice3":"Galicano Apacible",
		"choice4":"Mariano Ponce",
		"correct":"Galicano Apacible"
	},
	{
		"id":"54",
		"question":"The newspaper of the Katipunan. ",
		"choice1":"Kartilla",
		"choice2":"La Solidaridad",
		"choice3":"España en Filipinas",
		"choice4":"Kalayaan",
		"correct":"Kalayaan"
	},
	{
		"id":"55",
		"question":"Led the successful attack in Kawit on August 31, 1896.",
		"choice1":"Apolinario Mabini",
		"choice2":"Jose Rizal",
		"choice3":"Emilio Aguinaldo",
		"choice4":"Andres Bonifacio",
		"correct":"Emilio Aguinaldo"
	},
	{
		"id":"56",
		"question":"The Supremo of Katipunan.",
		"choice1":"Apolinario Mabini",
		"choice2":"Jose Rizal",
		"choice3":"Emilio Aguinaldo",
		"choice4":"Andres Bonifacio",
		"correct":"Andres Bonifacio"
	},
	{
		"id":"57",
		"question":"Bonifacio and his brother Procorpio were shot at?",
		"choice1":"Mount Tala",
		"choice2":"Barangay Limbon",
		"choice3":"Indang",
		"choice4":"Imus",
		"correct":"La Solidaridad"
	},
	{
		"id":"58",
		"question":"Destroyed the Spanish fleet without loss of a single ship or life.",
		"choice1":"John D. Long",
		"choice2":"George Dewey",
		"choice3":"Arthur McArthur",
		"choice4":"Primo De Vera",
		"correct":"George Dewey"
	},
	{
		"id":"59",
		"question":"Launched the largest offensive against Bataan",
		"choice1":"John D. Long",
		"choice2":"George Dewey",
		"choice3":"General Homma",
		"choice4":"Primo De Vera",
		"correct":"General Homma"
	},
	{
		"id":"60",
		"question":"General King surrendered Bataan to Japanese.",
		"choice1":"April 3, 1942",
		"choice2":"April 9, 1942",
		"choice3":"April 3, 1924",
		"choice4":"April 9, 1924",
		"correct":"April 9, 1942"
	},
		{
		"id":"61",
		"question":"The first to establish a guerilla organization.",
		"choice1":"General Homma",
		"choice2":"General MacArthur",
		"choice3":"Walter M. Cushing",
		"choice4":"George Dewey",
		"correct":"Walter M. Cushing"
	},
		{
		"id":"62",
		"question":"Largest Guerilla Organization",
		"choice1":"HUKBALAHAP",
		"choice2":"KALIBAPI",
		"choice3":"PCPI",
		"choice4":"PCAU",
		"correct":"HUKBALAHAP"
	},
		{
		"id":"63",
		"question":"Executed by the Japanese for refusal to collaborate with them.",
		"choice1":"Jose Abad Santos",
		"choice2":"Pedro Abad Santos",
		"choice3":"Miguel de Legazpi",
		"choice4":"Antonio Luna",
		"correct":"Jose Abad Santos"
	},
		{
		"id":"64",
		"question":"Lt. Hiroo Onoda surrendered to President Marcos.",
		"choice1":"June 10, 1974",
		"choice2":"April 9, 1942",
		"choice3":"March 10, 1974",
		"choice4":"March 9, 1974",
		"correct":"March 10, 1974"
	},
		{
		"id":"65",
		"question":"Gen. MacArthur formally reestablished the Commonwealth government.",
		"choice1":"September 4, 1958",
		"choice2":"April 9, 1942",
		"choice3":"January 9, 1948",
		"choice4":"October 23, 1944",
		"correct":"October 23, 1944"
	},
		{
		"id":"66",
		"question":"Japan attacked the Pearl Harbor.",
		"choice1":"December 7, 1941",
		"choice2":"April 9, 1942",
		"choice3":"January 9, 1948",
		"choice4":"October 23, 1944",
		"correct":"December 7, 1941"
	},
	{
		"id":"67",
		"question":"Last election under the Commonwealth government.",
		"choice1":"April 23, 1946",
		"choice2":"October 23, 1944",
		"choice3":"April 3, 1924",
		"choice4":"January 24, 1946",
		"correct":"April 23, 1946"
	},
	{
		"id":"68",
		"question":"Established the Agricultural Credit Cooperatives Financing Administration(ACCFA)",
		"choice1":"President Quezon",
		"choice2":"President Roxas",
		"choice3":"President Quirino",
		"choice4":"President Macapagal",
		"correct":"President Quirino"
	},	
	{
		"id":"69",
		"question":"Champion of the Masses",
		"choice1":"President Quezon",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Magsaysay",
		"choice4":"President Roxas",
		"correct":"President Magsaysay"
	},	
	{
		"id":"70",
		"question":"Launched the Filipino First Policy.",
		"choice1":"President Garcia",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Magsaysay",
		"choice4":"President Roxas",
		"correct":"President Garcia"
	},
	{
		"id":"71",
		"question":"Died in a plane crash in Mount Manungal.",
		"choice1":"President Garcia",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Magsaysay",
		"choice4":"President Roxas",
		"correct":"President Magsaysay"
	},
	{
		"id":"72",
		"question":"Negotiated  and granted amnesty to the Huks.",
		"choice1":"President Garcia",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Magsaysay",
		"choice4":"President Roxas",
		"correct":"President Quirino"
	},
	{
		"id":"73",
		"question":"Formed the Emergency Employment Administration(EEA) to solve the unemployment problem.",
		"choice1":"President Garcia",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Magsaysay",
		"choice4":"President Macapagal",
		"correct":"President Macapagal"
	},
	{
		"id":"74",
		"question":"Owned by the Sultan of Sulu.",
		"choice1":"Sabah",
		"choice2":"Sarawak",
		"choice3":"Borneo",
		"choice4":"Malaya",
		"correct":"Sabah"
	},
	{
		"id":"75",
		"question":"Introduced great changes in the general conditions of the country.",
		"choice1":"President Garcia",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Marcos",
		"choice4":"President Roxas",
		"correct":"President Marcos"
	},
	{
		"id":"76",
		"question":"Provided free trade relations between the Philippines and United States.",
		"choice1":"Bell Trade Law",
		"choice2":"Jones Law",
		"choice3":"Murphy Law",
		"choice4":"Forbes Law",
		"correct":"Bell Trade Law"
	},
	{
		"id":"77",
		"question":"Negotiated  and granted amnesty to the Huks.",
		"choice1":"President Garcia",
		"choice2":"President Quirino",
		"choice3":"President Magsaysay",
		"choice4":"President Roxas",
		"correct":"President Quirino"
	},
	{
		"id":"78",
		"question":"President Marcos declared Martial Law.",
		"choice1":"September 22, 1972",
		"choice2":"October 21, 1972",
		"choice3":"November 22, 1972",
		"choice4":"September 21, 1972",
		"correct":"September 21, 1972"
	},
	{
		"id":"79",
		"question":"Proclaimed the New Republic.",
		"choice1":"June 30, 1981",
		"choice2":"July 30, 1981",
		"choice3":"August 30, 1981",
		"choice4":"September 30, 1981",
		"correct":"June 30, 1981"
	},
	{
		"id":"80",
		"question":"The formidable political opponent of President Marcos.",
		"choice1":"Corazon Aquino",
		"choice2":"Ninoy Aquino",
		"choice3":"Sergio Osmeña",
		"choice4":"Diosdado Macapagal",
		"correct":"Ninoy Aquino"
	},
	{
		"id":"81",
		"question":"Administers the financial affairs of the country.",
		"choice1":"Banco De Oro",
		"choice2":"Central Bank of the Philippines",
		"choice3":"Bank of the Philippine Island",
		"choice4":"Land Bank",
		"correct":"Central Bank of the Philippines"
	},
	{
		"id":"82",
		"question":"A peacefull rally by people from all walks of life forced President Marcos to leave the country.",
		"choice1":"People Power",
		"choice2":"Human Power",
		"choice3":"Manila Revolution",
		"choice4":"Power Revolution",
		"correct":"People Power"
	},
	{
		"id":"83",
		"question":"The greatest muralist in the history of Philippine Art.",
		"choice1":"Hernando R. Ocampo",
		"choice2":"Carlos Francisco",
		"choice3":"Carlos Manansala",
		"choice4":"Hernando Legazpi",
		"correct":"Carlos Francisco"
	},
	{
		"id":"84",
		"question":"Proclaimed as National Artist posthumously  in 1973 for his contribution to the development of Tagalog prose.",
		"choice1":"Amado Fernandez",
		"choice2":"Fernando Amorsolo",
		"choice3":"Amado Hernandez",
		"choice4":"Pedro Tolentino",
		"correct":"Amado Hernandez"
	},
	{
		"id":"85",
		"question":"The first public bank in the Philippines.",
		"choice1":"Rodriguez Bank",
		"choice2":"Bank of the Philippine Island",
		"choice3":"Banco Español-Filipino de Isabel II",
		"choice4":"Banco De Oro",
		"correct":"Banco Español-Filipino de Isabel II"
	},
	{
		"id":"86",
		"question":"The Great Plebeian.",
		"choice1":"Emilio Aguinaldo",
		"choice2":"Marcelo Del Pilar",
		"choice3":"Andres Bonifacio",
		"choice4":"Apolinario Mabini",
		"correct":"Andres Bonifacio"
	},
	{
		"id":"87",
		"question":"Told the Spanish authorities of the existence of the Katipunan.",
		"choice1":"Pio Valenzuela",
		"choice2":"Juan Ramos",
		"choice3":"Padre Mariano Gil",
		"choice4":"Teodoro Plata",
		"correct":"Padre Mariano Gil"
	},
	{
		"id":"88",
		"question":"Insulted Bonifacio in Tejeros Convention.",
		"choice1":"Emilio Aguinaldo",
		"choice2":"Pio Valenzuela",
		"choice3":"Artemio Ricarte",
		"choice4":"Daniel Tirona",
		"correct":"Daniel Tirona"
	},	
	{
		"id":"89",
		"question":"The Declaration of Independence was read by___",
		"choice1":"Artemio Ricarte",
		"choice2":"Daniel Tirona",
		"choice3":"Ambrosio Bautista",
		"choice4":"Pio Valenzuela",
		"correct":"June 30, 1981"
	},
	{
		"id":"90",
		"question":"First Civil Governor.",
		"choice1":"George Dewey",
		"choice2":"Wesly Merritt",
		"choice3":"Elwell Otis",
		"choice4":"Arthur MacArthur",
		"correct":"Elwell Otis"
	},
	{
		"id":"91",
		"question":"The last military governor.",
		"choice1":"George Dewey",
		"choice2":"Wesly Merritt",
		"choice3":"Elwell Otis",
		"choice4":"Arthur MacArthur",
		"correct":"Arthur MacArthur"
	},
	{
		"id":"92",
		"question":"The last American governor-general of the Philippines.",
		"choice1":"Frank Murphy",
		"choice2":"Wesly Merritt",
		"choice3":"George Dern",
		"choice4":"Arthur MacArthur",
		"correct":"Frank Murphy"
	},
	{
		"id":"93",
		"question":"The first law passed by the Philippine Assembly.",
		"choice1":"National Defense Act",
		"choice2":"National Disaster Act",
		"choice3":"National Security Act",
		"choice4":"National Safety Act",
		"correct":"National Defense Act"
	},
	{
		"id":"94",
		"question":"Established to promulgate national educational policies.",
		"choice1":"National Defense Act",
		"choice2":"National Board of Education",
		"choice3":"National Education Act",
		"choice4":"Board of Education",
		"correct":"National Board of Education"
	},
	{
		"id":"95",
		"question":"The Road Building Governor.",
		"choice1":"George Dewey",
		"choice2":"Wesly Merritt",
		"choice3":"Elwell Otis",
		"choice4":"Cameron Forbes",
		"correct":"Cameron Forbes"
	},
	{
		"id":"96",
		"question":"Introduced the system of public education to eradicate illiteracy among the filipinos.",
		"choice1":"Spaniards",
		"choice2":"Americans",
		"choice3":"British",
		"choice4":"Chinese",
		"correct":"Americans"
	},
	{
		"id":"97",
		"question":"The first national election was held on ",
		"choice1":"February 8, 1935",
		"choice2":"June 19, 1935",
		"choice3":"September 17, 1935",
		"choice4":"March 23, 1935",
		"correct":"September 17, 1935"
	},
	{
		"id":"98",
		"question":"The bravest and most famous American guerilla leader in the Philippines that was assigned to organize all the guerilla leaders in Mindanao.",
		"choice1":"George Dewey",
		"choice2":"Wendel Fertig",
		"choice3":"Elwell Otis",
		"choice4":"Arthur MacArthur",
		"correct":"Wendell fertig"
	},
	{
		"id":"99",
		"question":"Inaugurated on September 25, 1943.",
		"choice1":"National Assembly",
		"choice2":"Independence",
		"choice3":"Commonwealth government",
		"choice4":"Philippine Commission",
		"correct":"National Assembly"
	},
	{
		"id":"100",
		"question":" When did the Philippines become independent?",
		"choice1":"A. 4 July 1776",
		"choice2":"B. 4 July 1946",
		"choice3":"C. 14 August 1947",
		"choice4":"D. 1 January 1984",
		"correct":"B. 4 July 1946"
	}
	
	];
	
	